Billionaire to Dole Out $9M in 'Serious Social Experiment'
It is said that money doesn't buy happiness, but a Japanese billionaire thinks it might at least cheer some people up.
Just a couple of weeks after Zozo Town founder Yusaku Maezawa donated more than $18 million to a Japanese city hit hard by a typhoon, the fashion-minded entrepreneur is back in the news with another giveaway.
According to Reuters news agency, Maezawa ponied up $9 million and distributed bundles of $9,000 to 1,000 lucky recipients.
The people were chosen at random after they retweeted his New Year’s Day tweet on the matter.
"It's a serious social experiment," Maezawa said in an accompanying YouTube video,
adding he hopes this initiative piques the interest of those in academia and economics.
Maezawa has always been curious about the overall concept of universal basic income, also known as UBI.
This was an idea often floated by former US presidential candidate Andrew Yang.
UBI is when the citizens of a nation receive a regular, guaranteed payment from the government.
Maezawa is interested in how a similar idea would affect people's overall well-being and happiness. An economist tells Reuters that what Maezawa is doing is somewhat different than the Universal Basic Income idea. Unlike UBI, it's just a one-time payment to each recipient. Also, at the moment in Japan, people can still find a job quite easily due to its tight labor market. Still, Maezawa wants to see how his "winners" react. "What happens if someone who can't help themselves with their own power is given money... to rebuild their lives?" he tweeted. "Can they turn their life around?"